A Guide to the Papers of John Kelly 1947-1949
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of John Kelly 1947-1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4151
This collection consists of 17 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift from Mr. John Kelly of Cismont, Virginia, on 2 February 1953. The material was orignially part of an exhibit mounted by the University of Virginia Bibliographical Society, of which John Kelly was a charter member. It was later donated to the University.
Biographical/Historical Information
John Kelley worked at different times in his life as an editor, a market analyst, and a professor of literature and creative writing at Marymount College in New York and at the University of Maryland. During World War II he served as an economist on the United States Government Board of Economic Warfare. Kelly graduated from Yale University in 1934. He received a B.A. degree in 1937 and an M.A. degree in 1941 from Cambridge University (Kings College), and undertook special graduate studies at Harvard University in 1937-1938. Born in Jersey City, New Jersey, in 1913, Kelly lived for many years in Cismont, Virginia, and died in New York City in 1966. His other writings include a novel published in 1947 entitled All Souls' Night and articles and book reviews for various newspapers and journals.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of John Kelly are from various stages in the development of his novel Alexander's Feast which was published in 1949. Materials include the orignial holograph manuscript, typescript drafts, galley proofs, page proofs, signatures, dust wrappers, and other items related to the production of the novel.
Contents List
- Alexander's Feast, Chaps. 1-27, (originally titled A Love in Desolation) 1946-1947, AMs (Box 1)
  (3 folders)
- Alexander's Feast,(originally titled A Love in Desolation), typescript of Chapter 1, with author's corrections 1947, TMs (Box 1)
- Alexander's Feast,(originally titled The Fatal Friends), First draft w/author's corrections 1947, TMsS (Box 1)
- Alexander's Feast,(originally titled The Fatal Friends), Second draft with author's corrections ca. 1947, TMsS (Box 2)
- Alexander's Feast 1947, Galley Proofs (Box 3)
- Alexander's Feast, with author's corrections 1947, Galley Proofs (Box 3)
- Alexander's Feast 1947, Page Proofs (Box 3)
- Alexander's Feast, with author's corrections 1947, Page Proofs (Box 3)
- Alexander's Feast, Chapters 1-28 1947, TMs Setting Copy (Box 3)
- Alexander's Feast ca. 1949, Uncut Signatures (Box 4)
- Alexander's Feast ca. 1949, Cut Signatures (Box 4)
- Alexander's Feast, with casing 1949, Bound Signatures (Box 4)
- Alexander's Feast, with engraved casing 1949, Bound Signatures (Box 4)
- Galley Proofs and Page Proofs for Dust Covers of Alexander's Feastca.1949 (Box 4)
- Notes and Page Proofs re Development of Title and Dedication Pages (include printer's instructions) 1949 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous 1948-1949 (Box 4)